this problem has given us
five lines of code and we need to
determine
what each line of code will evaluate to
first on line 1 we have variable
assignment
the variable x is being assigned to the
integer 2.
variable assignment is going to return
the value that is assigned
so in this case we expect the return
value to be 2.
let's hop into irb
and we can see this in action so we'll
assign a variable
x to the integer 2
irb shows us that this evaluates to
2.
moving on to the code on line 3
in this line of code we're assigning the
variable x to
2 but we're also invoking the puts
method
the put s method will output the return
value of this assignment so it will
output
2 however the put s method always
returns
nil so this expression on line three
will evaluate to nil let's hop back to
irb
we invoke put us and we pass in that
assignment
we can see that it output 2 and returned
nil
moving on to our code on line 5 again we
see variable assignment
we are assigning the variable name to
the string joe
and we're going to output the return
value of that assignment
similarly to what we saw in our last
code example
however this time we're using the method
p
this method will output its argument and
then return its argument
so we expect that this line of code will
evaluate
to the string joe
we're using p to output the return of
this variable assignment
we see the output and below we also see
that the string joe is returned
moving down to the code on line 7 this
is simple variable assignment again we
are assigning the variable
4 to the string 4.
so in this case we expect that the
expression will evaluate to the string
4. we'll test it out in irb
and we can see that the string 4 is
returned
in our last example we assign the string
nothing to a variable something
and we pass the return value of that
assignment to the method
print print will output the return value
of this assignment
and then return nil
we'll hop into irb one last time to
demonstrate this
our output and return here look a little
bit different in this example
because the print method does not append
a new line onto its output
and that's why we see the output and the
return value here on the same line
so we've successfully determined what
all five of these expressions evaluate
too